# **MICKEY CAMARCO**

631-278-0048 | Philadelphia, PA | Mickey.Camarco@gmail.com | mickeycamarco.com | linkedin.com/in/mcamarco

## SUMMARY

Experienced professional adept at technical channel enablement, pre-sales solutions engineering, and business analysis. Demonstrated success in exceeding sales targets, driving partner-sourced revenue, and building strategic partnerships. Proven skills in delivering technical presentations, influencing product roadmaps, and innovating solutions.

## **TECHNICAL LANGUAGES**

HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, DOM Manipulation, APIs, jQuery, JSON, AJAX, Git, Node.js, ES6, OOP, Express.js, MySQL, MVC Paradigm, Sequelize, Testing, React.js, NoSQL

## **SOFTWARE / APPLICATIONS**

Nintex Process Platform, Canto, Expensify, Millennia FileStar, MRI, Nexus, VTS (View The Space), Atlassian Jira & Confluence, SharePoint Online (O365), GitHub/GitLab, PowerBI, Concur, Microsoft Dynamics, Asana, Dropbox, Camtasia, Google Suite, Salesforce CRM.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### Technical Channel Enablement Manager | Nintex | Remote | July 2022 – February 2023

- Acted as the central source for product enablement, providing technical expertise and solutions.
- Managed and executed technical partner enablement programs, including training and resources.
- Conducted engaging training exercises to equip teams with necessary knowledge and skills.
- Monitored and communicated technical roadblocks to influence product roadmap.
- Educated channel partners on the technical value proposition of multiple products.
- Exceeded Partner-Sourced revenue guota by 105% in H1.
- Developed comprehensive go-to-market plans in collaboration with Strategic Partner Managers.
- Exceeded Partner Qualified Lead (PQL) goal by 15%.
- Successfully delivered 41 field marketing events, surpassing the goal of 35.

#### Solutions Engineer | Nintex | Remote | April 2021 - July 2022

- Achieved 100+% of sales goals with each aligned Account Executive.
- Researched and identified customer business problems, providing tailored pre-sales solutions and technical presentations.
- Provided product demonstrations and technical presentations.
- Monitored technical roadblocks to influence product roadmap.
- Engaged in thought leadership at conferences, webinars, and community engagements.

## Business Analyst / Product Manager | Silverstein Properties | New York | May 2019 - April 2019

- Implemented seamless integration for real-time Power BI dashboards.
- Developed a comprehensive knowledge base for software applications and projects, including detailed how-to guides and troubleshooting solutions using Confluence.
- Served as Scrum Master, effectively leading projects and coordinating sprints using JIRA.
- Developed automated Form/Workflow solutions during COVID-19 to address urgent & complex needs.

#### Diversity, Equity & Inclusion Team Member | Silverstein Properties | New York | July 2019 - April 2021

- Developed data-driven strategies to position Silverstein Properties as an employer of choice.
- Created anonymous surveys to gather employee demographics.
- Transformed survey findings into written analysis and presentation.

Inside Sales Account Manager (Temp) | Hi-Tech Fasteners Corp | New York | December 2018 - May 2019

- Developed, cultivated, and managed customer relationships, leading to increased sales and inquiries.
- Maintained the company website and managed inquiries.

## Sales Associate | Metrofab Pipe, Inc | New York | April 2016 - September 2018

- Promoted to Sales Associate within 4 months, providing comprehensive sales support, handling client relations, and managing inventory.
- Conducted client demonstrations and performed market research.
  Provided full range of sales support for President, VP, and Office Administrator.
- Handled incoming orders, managed customer service and inventory, and created calendar plans for sales and administration.

## **PROJECTS**

## The 19th Hole | github.com/mcamarco/the-19th-hole | mcamarco.github.io/the-19th-hole/

- Full-stack application using Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, Sequelize ORM, and Handlebars.js. Collaborated on RESTful API development, database implementation, and responsive UI.

## Portfoli-Yo | github.com/mcamarco/Portfoli-Yo | portfoli-yo.herokuapp.com

- Full-stack application using Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, Sequelize ORM, and Handlebars.js. Contributed to RESTful API development, database functionality, and responsive UI.

## Consulting Website | github.com/mcamarco/camarcoconsulting | www.camarcoconsulting.com

 MERN stack single-page application for Camarco Consulting LLC. Developed user-friendly interface, implemented React components, integrated GraphQL for data retrieval, and deployed on Heroku with polished UI.

# **EDUCATION**

- Penn LPS Coding Boot Camp, University Of Pennsylvania
- B.S. Business Administration, Farmingdale State College (Minor: Business Law)
- Project Management For Professionals, NYU School of Professional Studies

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Full Stack Web Developer University of Pennsylvania
- Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) LinkedIn Learning
- Technical Sales: The Role of the Sales Engineer LinkedIn Learning
- Process Automation Practitioner Nintex
- Workflow Cloud Practitioner Nintex